（カカシ）敵の気配が消えた。
There's no sign of the enemy.
（ガイ）味方も見当たらないが
戦力が散りすぎている。
I don't see our forces either.
We're too scattered.
各部隊を集結させるべきだろう。
We must gather the troops together.
そうだな。
You're right.
カカシ隊長。
Captain Kakashi!
ユルイの部隊から救援要請です。
Yurui's unit is requesting
reinforcements!
オモイがいる部隊か…
どうした？
Omoi's in that unit.
What's up?
現在　林檎雨由利と
交戦中とのことです。
They're engaged in a fight
with Ameyuri Ringo!
林檎雨由利…。
Ameyuri Ringo...
忍刀七人衆
雷刀　牙の使い手か。
One of the Seven
Ninja Swordsmen
who wields
the Lightning Blade, Fang...
俺が行く。
俺も行こう。
I'll go!
I'm going too.
林檎雨由利は　雷遁使いだ。
Ameyuri Ringo uses
the Lightning Style.
俺の雷遁で
相殺できるかもしれない。
I may be able to neutralize her
with my own Lightning Style.
always chasing after your shadow
itsu made mo oikakete iru anata no zanzo wo
when you dream, your face looks like it did before
yume ni miru yokogao ha ano koro no mama de
you run into the tall grass and disappear
se no takai kusanami ni hashiri satte kieta
I push through the memories and follow you
omoidasu kioku wo kakewake atoo uboku ha
it's frustrating as I run out of breath and in the end I'm unable to reach you
modokashiku mo iki wo kirashite saigo ha todokazu ni
far away
tooku
how many years ago was it?
nannenmae no koto desho
I left my heart at that place
nidoto modorenai ano basho ni
where I can never return
oite kite shimatta boku no kokoro sa
if this is a dream, if I can't get it back
moshimo yume naraba tori modosenai no nara
then how can I tell you how I feel?
kono kimochi ha do shite utaereba ii no
I'm still chasing after the shadow from that day
imadani oikakete iru ano hi no zanzo wo
though I spend my days in sorrow
kanashimi ni ake kurenagara mo ima
I'll live on in this world without you
anata naki sekai de boku wa ikiru yo
The Lightning Blade:
Ameyuri Ringo!
（雨由利）みんな隠れてないで。
Stop hiding!
誰か私のハートを
ビビっとさせるヤツはいないの？
Isn't there anyone here that can send
shockwaves through my heart?
雷遁　雷牙！
Lightning Style: Lighting Fang!
臆病者はタイプじゃないよ。
Cowards aren't my type!
（ユルイ）まだ増援は来ないのか？
Where are the reinforcements?!
お仕置きに
全員　黒焦げにしてあげる。
As punishment...
I'm going to burn you to a crisp!
雷遁　サンダーゲート！
Lighting Style: Thunder Gate!
うわ～！
（ヌルイ）ユルイ！
Yurui!
しっかりしろ　ユルイ！
Hang on, Yurui!
（ユルイ）ダメだ…
もう暗くなってきてやがる…。
It's over...
Everything's... going dark...
あきらめるな　ユルイ。
もうすぐ増援が来るぞ。
Don't give up, Yurui!
Help is on the way!
ヌルイ　あとを　頼んだ…。
Nurui... It's in...
your hands now...
ユルイ　ユルイ！
Yurui! Yurui!
（オモイ）くそっ　もううんざりだ。
Damn it! I've had it with this!
何人死んだんだ！
How many have died already?
これが　戦争なのかよ…。
Is this what war is?!
生き残ったのは
たったこれだけか。
Are we the only survivors?
どうやら　そのようですね。
It looks that way.
これからは　俺が指揮をとる。
I'll take command from now on.
この中じゃ
俺がいちばん先輩だからな。
I have seniority here.
（カユイ）林檎雨由利は
別方向の小隊を追ってった。
Ameyuri Ringo went after
the other platoon
in the other direction.
すぐに戻ってくるぞ。
But she'll be back.
早く　どうするか決めないと。
We have to decide
what to do quickly.
それは決まってる　退却だ。
It's obvious. We retreat.
逃げ出すんですか？
Are we running away?
たかだか忍刀１人に。
Just because she's one of
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen?
まさか　林檎雨由利と
やりあおうなんてこと→
Are you suggesting we take on
Ameyuri Ringo?
言い出すんじゃねえだろうな。
それは…。
Well...
お前らしくねえな　オモイ。
That's not like you, Omoi.
お前は　俺と同じ
慎重派だと思ってたんだが。
I thought you were
the cautious type, just like me.
戦争は　敵討ちの場じゃねえ。
War is not the place
for revenge.
それに忍刀と俺たちが
やりあったって→
And besides,
we don't have a chance
勝てるわけねえだろ。
アイツらは　象か虎。
against someone with
a Ninja Blade.
They are like elephants and tigers.
We're mere ants.
俺たちは　ただのアリンコだ。
じゃあ　何のために
俺たちは　いるんです？
Then why the hell are we here?!
うぬぼれるな　オモイ
英雄にでもなったつもりか？
Don't get full of yourself, Omoi.
Are you trying to be a hero now?
とにかく　ここの指揮官は俺だ。
In any case, I'm the leader now!
林檎雨由利を牽制しつつ
撤退する。
We'll create a diversion for
Ameyuri Ringo and make our escape.
つまんないの
誰も私を　ビビッとさせてくれない。
How boring... Not a single soul
to give me a thrill.
そういえば　まだ　向こうに
２～３匹　残ってたっけ。
Oh, that's right.
There were two or three
more back there.
私のタイプいないかなぁ？
Maybe they're more my type.
先ほど見えた落雷。
That flash of lightning earlier...
林檎雨由利の雷遁の術に
間違いなさそうだな。
There's no doubt it was
Ameyuri Ringo's Lightning Style.
一瞬でこの広範囲を…。
Damage of this scope,
in an instant.
これでは　中忍クラスが
１００人がかりでも勝てまい。
Not even a hundred chunin
could defeat her.
わからないよ
こんなときだからこそ→
Well, who knows...
In a desperate moment like this,
隠れた英雄が
出るかもしれない。
a hero could rise up
from among them.
散り散りになった小隊たちに→
Wishing for the survival of
our scattered comrades
生きててほしいという
気持はわかるがな→
is one thing.
現状を見ると
今は気休めにしか聞こえん。
Hoping for a hero is
just wishful thinking.
とにかく戦いの跡からして
林檎雨由利は北上してる。
Whatever the case,
judging from the traces of battle,
Ameyuri Ringo is headed north.
その先に　生き残りがいるはずだ。
急ごう！
There should be survivors
beyond that.
Let's hurry!
《クソッ！　このまま　どんどん逃げて
結局　世界一周しちまって→
Damn it... If we keep running
and running...
Pretty soon,
we'll circle the globe.
何周も　何周も逃げ回るうちに→
And if we keep circling
the globe over and over again,
なんで戦いを続けてんのかも
忘れて→
we'll forget why the hell
we're fighting.
誰も俺が生きているなんて
思わなくなって…。
And no one will think
that I'm still alive.
俺は　ただ死ぬまで
ずっと逃げ続けてて…。
I'll keep running and
running until I die.
そんなことなら　いっそ…》
If that's the case, then...
隊長　まだ退却を
続けるつもりなんですか？
Captain! Are we still gonna
keep running away?
逃げていれば　援軍が来て→
If we keep running,
maybe the reinforcements will arrive
ヤツを　なんとかしてくれるかも
しれねえ。
and take care of that bitch.
《チッ　他力本願かよ》
Waiting for others to bail us out?!
何やってるんですか？
What are you doing?
逃げるっつっても
戦った体裁はとっとかねえと→
We have to make it look
like we put up a fight...
戦争が終わったとき
何言われるか　わからねえからな。
Otherwise, who knows what
they'll say after the war.
《くだらねえ　見栄かよ。
How stupid. Talk about ego...
それに　こんなバレバレの罠。
And this trap is so obvious!
敵に俺たちの逃げている方向を
知らせるようなもんだぜ。
It's like telling the enemy exactly
which way we're running.
やっぱり　コイツなんかに
ついていったら→
Nothing good's gonna come
from following this guy!
ろくなことにならねえ》
《フフフ！　私から逃げようったって
無理なんだから》
You can't run away from me.
何よ　この罠！
They call this a trap?
私のこと　ナメてるわけ？
They must think I'm stupid.
絶対に逃がさないんだから！
I'm never going to let you go!
そもそも　林檎雨由利ってのは
どんなヤツなんです？
Just who is
this Ameyuri Ringo anyway?
雷遁使いの天才と呼ばれた女だ。
A woman known to be an exceptional user
of the Lightning Style.
不治の病で早死にしたらしいが→
Although she died young
from an incurable disease,
狙った獲物は
絶対に逃がさなかったって噂だ。
it's said she never lost her prey.
逃げ切れない相手？
There's no escaping her?
余計なことを言うな　カユイ！
That's enough, Kayui!
ヌルイ…　アンタそれがわかってて！
Nurui!
You knew this, and still...
来たぞ！
Here she comes!
クソッ！　思ってたより速かったな。
Damn it!
She's faster than I thought.
《そら追いつかれるさ。
こんなヌルイことしてたら！》
Of course, she's gonna catch up!
This is such a lame strategy!
おおっ！
うわっ！
♪～
逃げ切れない！
We can't outrun her!
戦いましょう！
いいや　ダメだ！
Let's fight!
No! It's no use!
それじゃ　いつまで
逃げるつもりなんです？
How far can we run?!
ヤツからは　逃げ切れないんでしょ！
She always gets her prey, right?!
そんなことはわかってる！
I know!
わかってるって…。
Well, do you know that our lives
are in your hands?!
俺たちの命はな
アンタにかかってるんだぞ！
だから退却している。
That's why we're retreating!
アンタ　それで忍か！
How can you call yourself
a shinobi?!
死んでった仲間のことを
考えたことがあるのか！
Have you even thought about
our fallen comrades?!
オモイ！　お前はヌルイを誤解してる。
Omoi! You don't understand Nurui!
ヌルイ！　アンタもアンタだ！
And Nurui, you too!
どうして…。
（ヌルイ）黙れカユイ！
Why don't...?!
Shut up, Kayui!
俺は…　もう逃げるなんて
ごめんだ！
I've...
had enough of running!
オモイ…。
Omoi...
知ってるんだぜ　ヌルイ。
I know... about your reputation
in the village, Nurui.
里での　アンタの評判くらい。
オモイ！　そのへんにしとけ！
Omoi! That's enough!
アンタは　慎重なふりしてる
臆病者だって。
That you being cautious is
just to hide your cowardice!
俺は慎重派だが　臆病者じゃねえ！
Well, I'm a cautious guy,
but I'm no coward!
やめろ　オモイ！
今　戦っても　ムダだ。
Stop it, Omoi!
Fighting is useless right now!
俺たちは　英雄になるなんてことは
できねえんだよ！
We can't be heroes!
そんなこと言われなくても
わかってますよ！
The thought didn't even
cross my mind!
でも　ずっと　ちらつくんだ。
I just keep seeing Yurui's face
as he was dying!
さっき死んでった　ユルイの顔が。
たとえ逃げのびたって→
And even if we escape somehow,
俺は　そんなものを見続けながら
生きていくなんて　ごめんだ！
I can't go on living with
that image
constantly flashing
through my mind.
やめろ　オモイ
今　戦ってもムダだ。
Stop it, Omoi!
Fighting is useless right now!
俺たちは英雄になるなんてことは
できねえんだよ。
We can't be heroes!
そんなこと　言われなくても
わかってますよ！
The thought didn't even
cross my mind!
でも　ずっと　ちらつくんだ。
I just keep seeing Yurui's face
as he was dying!
さっき死んでった
ユルイの顔が。
例え　逃げのびたって→
And even if we escape somehow,
俺は　そんなものを見続けながら
生きていくなんてごめんだ。
I can't go on living with
that image
constantly flashing
through my mind.
オモイ！
Omoi!
どうやら　まだ林檎雨由利は
誰かを追っているようだ。
Looks like Ameyuri Ringo is
still in pursuit of someone.
でも　まずいね。
This isn't good...
この先に
忍連合の部隊は誰もいない。
There aren't any Allied Shinobi
units beyond this point.
追われてる側は
ますます孤立するだけだ。
The pursued are only making
themselves more isolated.
急ごう！
Let's hurry!
うお～！
や～ん　いるじゃない。
Oh, here's one.
私に向かってきてくれる人が。
Someone who's willing to face me!
ユルイの敵！
I'm avenging Yurui!
なに？　もう逃げ出しちゃうの？
What? Running away so soon?
結局　この程度…。
You were so worthless after—!
なんてな
雲流　騙し斬り！
Fooled ya!
Cloud Style: Deception Slice!
って　騙されるか！
No one tricks me!
雷刀術　落雷！
Lightning Blade Jutsu!
Thunderbolt!
うお～！
《強え…　コイツに勝つには→
She's strong...
If I'm gonna beat her,
ビー様に教わった
あれを使うしか》
I have to use the one
Bee taught me!
((ビー：俺の剣術自慢。
My sword technique is
one to behold!
チケット１万
さばいてくれたら　俺のど自慢。
If you get 10,000 tickets sold,
and if you come and watch me rap
I'll help put your skill on the map.
お前だって　腕自慢。
それで本当に　ビー様。
You'll really teach me
your lethal blade technique?
教えてくれるんでしょうね？
必殺の剣。
((っつうか
雲隠れに１万人もいるのか？))
Hey, are there really 10,000 guys
in the Hidden Cloud?
はっきりズバリ　お前の剣術
パワーもキレも　中のチュー。
To put it bluntly,
your sword power and skill
ain't too much of a thrill.
俺は　ラップに夢中のチュー。
Unlike my rapping
which keeps feet a-stomping.
つまり俺は
まるで普通だってことですか？
In other words, you are saying
I'm average?
だけど騙し斬りだけ　センスキラリ。
Except your Deception Slice
which is divine.
それを　ノラリクラリ伸ばす展開
それが　俺の限界。
So polish that up and you'll be fine.
Now this lesson is at
the end of the line.
ようするに　俺の裏斬りを
もっと工夫するわけですね？
So you're telling me to tweak
my Deception Slice and make it better?
(イエー))
Yeah!
《それが　この術
裏霞斬り》
And the result of that is...
Hidden Mist Slice.
また向かってくる気？
Still not giving up?
ちょっとは
骨がありそうじゃない。
At least you have some backbone.
《この剣は　どこから出てくるか
太刀筋を読ませない剣》
This sword style makes it difficult
to read the path of the blade!
ワオ！
《この術の本気はここからだ》
I'm just beginning to
execute this jutsu!
《俺流　裏霞斬り改》
My personal style...
Hidden Mist Slice, Kai!
（オモイ）これならかわせねえ！
Let's see you counter this!
Huh? They're all decoys?!
（雨由利）全部オトリ？
とった！
雷遁　爆雷！
Gotcha!
Lightning Style! Depth Charge!
うわ！
けっこうやるわね。
You're not bad at all.
普通の人なら
やられてたけど→
Most guys would be dead.
ごめんね　私すんごく強くって。
Sorry, but I'm really strong.
（ヌルイ）オモイ！
Omoi!
今は殺さないでいてあげる。
I won't kill you just yet.
だって私　好きなものは
最後に食べるタイプなの。
Because I'm the type of person
who saves the things
I like to eat for last.
来るな！　ヌルイ　カユイ！
Don't come!
Nurui! Kayui!
ヌルイ…。
Nurui...
ヌルイ　大丈夫か　ヌルイ？
Nurui!
Are you all right, Nurui?!
この　余計なことしやがって。
Did you have to act so foolishly?
すまない　俺のために。
I'm sorry... For my sake...
そうさ　全部ぶち壊しだぜ。
Damn right. Everything's ruined.
いいか　よく聞け　オモイ。
Now listen carefully...
Omoi...
見つけた！
Found you!
逃がさないんだから。
I won't let you get away.
《ダメだ　勝てる気がしねえ。
つうか　俺じゃ勝てねえ！》
It's no good...
I don't feel like I can win!
More like, I can't beat her!
大丈夫か　カユイ！
はい。
Are you all right, Kayui?!
Yes...
他に　まだ誰かいるのか？
Is there anyone else with you?
ヌルイとオモイが　この先に。
Nurui and Omoi are up ahead...
林檎雨由利も　そこか。
Ameyuri Ringo is there too, huh?
そこで　ヤツを仕留めます。
And they're going to
bring her down.
《ヌルイの言うとおりだ！
Nurui was right.
俺には最初から
逃げるしか方法はなかった！
Running away was my only option!
俺は英雄じゃねえ！
なんて　バカだったんだ　俺は》
I'm no hero!
How could I have been so stupid?!
ぐわ～っ！
さあ　覚悟はいい？
Now then, are you prepared?
わかったよ。
やりゃいいんだろ　やりゃ！
Fine... You want me to fight?
I'll fight then.
その努力は認めてあげるわ。
You're determined.
I'll give you that.
《間に合ってくれよ！》
Please let us get there in time!
コイツは俺が　いや　俺たちが
倒さなきゃいけねえんだ！
I have to, I mean,
we have to bring her down.
ヌルイ…　ユルイ！
Nurui... Yurui...
私を倒すなんて
まだ　そんな寝言　言ってるの？
Bring me down?
Are you still talking nonsense?
テメエなんか
最初からなめてんだよ！
I planned to lick you
from the beginning!
なんつったって
今日の飴は林檎味だからな！
'Cuz my flavor today is apple candy
and your name means just that!
来いよ　お前の渾身の術で！
Bring it on with
your strongest jutsu!
うお～っ！
残念！　せっかく
私好みの男だったのに。
Too bad!
And you were my type too.
雷遁　サンダーゲート！
Lightning Style: Thunder Gate!
何これ！？
What is this?!
私を罠に？
You trapped me?!
ここは　もともと底なし沼だ。
This is actually a bottomless marsh.
一度はまったら
出られることはねえ。
Once you're stuck,
you'll never get out.
でも私の道連れに
なってくれるなんて　ステキ。
And you're coming with me?
What a gentleman!
((ユルイは　俺の親友だった。
Yurui was my friend.
公私混同してたのは俺さ。
I'm the one who let
personal feelings interfere.
俺は　ユルイの敵を…。
I wanted to avenge Yurui...
俺たちでヤツを倒す方法は
たった１つしかなかった。
There was only one way
for us to beat her.
この先に底なし沼がある。
There is a bottomless marsh
up ahead.
そこには土遁の蓋がしてある。
It's been covered with
an Earth Style lid.
そこでヤツが雷遁を使えば
ヤツは底なし沼に沈む。
If she uses her Lightning Style there,
she'll sink into
this bottomless marsh.
そこにヤツを引っ張り込む
作戦だった。
I planned to lure her there.
大戦に向けて　あらかじめ
俺とユルイとカユイで→
Yurui, Kayui and I had made
a number of traps
in preparation for a big battle.
いくつかの罠を作っておいたんだ。
それじゃあ　アンタ
逃げてたわけじゃ…。
So you... weren't running away?
オモイ　俺は自分の力量を知ってる。
Omoi, I know the limits
of my strength.
だが　この計画は　もうなしだ。
逃げろ。
But my plan won't work.
You must run away.
林檎雨由利は
俺がここで食い止める。
I'll stop Ameyuri Ringo here.
そんな体じゃ無理だ！
You can't in your condition!
それにヤツからは
どうせ逃げられないんだろ？
And besides, there's no
running away from her, right?!
(やめろ　オモイ！))
Stop... Omoi...
オモイ！
Omoi!
カカシさん　ガイさん！
Kakashi! Guy!
なんとか間に合ったようだな。
We made it in time.
引っ張り上げろ！
Pull him out.
私と一緒に
逝ってくれるんじゃないの？
Weren't you going to
come with me?
残念だが　またの機会にするよ。
Sorry, maybe another time.
今度　生まれ変わったら
好きなものは最初に食べるわ。
In my next life, I'll remember
to eat what I like first.
もうアンタが
生まれ変わることはねえ。
You won't be
reincarnated anymore.
これは餞別だ。
Here's a farewell gift from me...
ありがとう。
Thank you.
オモイ　俺の名はオモイだ。
Omoi... My name's Omoi.
オモイ…。
Omoi...
それは　お礼よ。
That's a thank-you gift
from me.
あの世で待ってるわ。
I'll be waiting for you
on the other side.
よくやった　オモイ。
You did well, Omoi.
You're a hero.
お前は英雄だ。
本当の英雄は　アンタだよ。
The real hero... is you.
やっぱり　いるもんだな
常に新しい英雄ってのが。
So there are new heroes,
after all.
いつ見ても　いいもんだ
男の熱い友情は。
It's always a heartwarming sight...
This deep bond between men.
（いのいち）カカシ　ガイ　聞いてくれ。
Kakashi, Guy...
Listen up.
I wanted to give you
advance notice.
お前たちには先に連絡しておく。
今　ナルトとビーが戦場に向かっている。
Naruto and Bee are heading
to the battlefront.
我々の説得も
ナルトには効かなかったようだ。
It seems nothing worked
to convince Naruto.
So, we're going to use
this opportunity to turn this war around!
だが　これを機会に
戦況を一気に立て直す。
Over and out!
以上だ。
聞いたか？　カカシ。
Did you hear that, Kakashi?
あぁ
とうとう動き出したようだね。
Yeah... They're finally on the move.
俺たちが待ちかねていた
英雄たちも。
The heroes we've waited
so long for.
I wonder why I can't fly
nande kanaa sora ga tobenai no wa
even though in my dreams, I have wings
yume no naka no boku wa hane ga haeten no ni
I'm going to surpass my limits and leave this place
genkai wo koete tobidasou koko kara
I'll drive away my loneliness with you
samishisa fuki tobasu kimi to kimi to
"I love you" and "good bye" have disappeared
i love you mo sayonara mo ienakatta
leaving me here incomplete
koko ni fukanzen na boku dake wo nokoshite
you still haven't taught me the song of love
ai no uta kimi ni mada tsutaetenai yo
of this dazzling world
dokomademo mabushiku kagayaku sekai wo
of this song
kono uta wo
Since days long past,
that location has been
a site reserved for sacred use.
And it's been referred to
as "The Hole."
The villagers charged with taking care
of the site have been slaughtered.
– What?
– That's so...!
Locate the perpetrator
and mete out
the appropriate punishment!
– All right!
– Yes, ma'am!
Next Time on
Naruto Shippuden: "Power - Episode 1"
It's been a while, Naruto...